pointroll.com 2015-12-30

# Privacy Notice - PointRoll

## Effective March 2015

PointRoll is an advertising and marketing solutions company that creates and distributes a variety of digital advertisements (“PointRoll Ads”) for advertisers and advertising agencies (“Advertisers”) by serving them to designated sites upon direction of the Advertisers (an “Ad Server”). PointRoll Ads are displayed across a variety of websites, applications and other digital platforms (e.g., digital signage) that are owned or operated by other third parties (“Publishers”). Advertisers and Publishers who complete our registration process are Members who can manage their accounts on this website, mobile site or apps (the “Site”). Please note that while we own and operate the PointRoll Site, we do not own or operate the website, application, or other digital platform operated by any Publisher. PointRoll Ads do not generally market PointRoll products, but are created for PointRoll’s clients to support their advertising campaigns. To help you better understand the landscape and key concepts of digital advertising, take a look at the Interactive Advertising Bureau’s [glossary](http://www.iab.net/wiki/index.php/Category:Glossary).

Please read this Privacy Notice to learn about PointRoll’s information collection practices and use both for this Site and for PointRoll Ads delivered digitally.

PointRoll does business exclusively in the United States. The Site and PointRoll Ads are directed exclusively to a U.S. audience.  

PointRoll participates in industry self-regulatory groups and adheres to guidelines such as those of the [Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA)](http://www.aboutads.info/), a cooperative of companies committed to building responsible advertising policies across the Internet. PointRoll is also a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). Users can obtain information about advertising service providers’ information collection practices, and opt out of such practices (and at the same time opt out of the collection practices of other, or all, NAI members) by following the opt out instructions at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.

**Consistent with these self-regulatory commitments, PointRoll respects users who wish to minimize cookies.** **PointRoll will not set cookies on user devices in contravention of a user’s browser’s cookie settings to decline all cookies or to accept cookies only from third parties.** **You can Opt Out of receiving cookies that enable the Viewer’s browser to receive targeted PointRoll Ads by clicking the Opt-Out image below.**

opt-out

If you have any questions about this privacy notice or PointRoll’s privacy practices, please contact Linda Carducci, lcarducc at tegna.com, Online Privacy Coordinator, PointRoll, TEGNA Law Department, 7950 Jones Branch Drive, McLean, VA 22107.

**Your California Privacy Rights.** California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits PointRoll’s customers who are California residents to request and obtain from PointRoll once a year, free of charge, information about the Personal Information (if any) PointRoll disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of Personal Information that were shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which PointRoll shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request, with information about where you saw the PointRoll Ad, in writing to: Linda Carducci, lcarducc at tegna.com, Online Privacy Coordinator, PointRoll, TEGNA Law Department, 7950 Jones Branch Drive, McLean, VA 22107.

**What is Personal Information or Personally Identifiable Information (PI/PII)?** For purposes of this Privacy Notice, PointRoll considers Personal Information to be information that can be used to contact or identify a natural person. Examples of PI include, but are not limited to: name, email address, postal address, telephone number, social security number, and credit card number.

**What is Non-Personal Information?** Non-Personal Information is any information other than Personal Information. For example, this may include information about how a user interacts with the Site, the user’s IP address or information about the user’s browser, operating system, or device.

**Changes.** If PointRoll changes this Privacy Notice in the future, PointRoll will post the changes to the Privacy Notice on this website and update the Effective Date of the Privacy Notice to reflect the date of the changes.

### 1\. FOR VISITORS TO THE POINTROLL SITE

**Collection on the Site.** PointRoll collects information that is generated automatically as a user navigates through the Site. For example, we collect IP addresses, device specific identification numbers, make and model of your device, wireless provider associated with your device, whether you downloaded an app, the source of the download of the App (for example, whether via a particular advertisement for the app), when the App is launched, how many times a particular page within the Site is visited, your device or computer’s connection to the Internet, and information about how many times a particular page within our Site is visited and which features of the Site you interact with. This information does not identify an individual, but tells us how many users visited the Site, downloaded an App, and used its features. We may also collect location information including GPS information from your device if the device transmits it. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor the Site to our visitors. PointRoll may collect Non-Personal Information of users through a variety of technologies and practices including PointRoll’s browser cookies, web beacons or similar technologies, or a third party’s browser cookies. A cookie is a small file that can be automatically stored on a computer when the computer’s browser views an advertisements or a website.

**PointRoll’s Cookies.** PointRoll’s Site uses several different cookies for different purposes on the Site. We use our own cookies, also known as “first party” cookies, for various purposes, including analyzing our servers’ interactions with your browser and for our own marketing purposes in marketing PointRoll’s ad development and serving services to our customers. Please note that we do not use “flash cookies” in connection with this Site.

**PointRoll’s Cookies Duration.** PointRoll Site currently sets cookies to be effective for no more than two years from the last interaction with a PointRoll domain or an Ad served by PointRoll. If you have concerns about historical cookies, we recommend that you clear your cookies using your web browser’s settings.

**Third Party Cookies.** In addition to our own cookies, our Site also use a limited number of third-party cookies, which we use for site analytics that allow us to improve this Site and to enable social media sharing, site bookmarking, video functionality, measurements, tracking and re-targeting. PointRoll does not create these cookies, which collect technical information about computers visiting this Site, and these third-party cookies remain active for a period set by the third party entity with which they originate. Please read below for more information regarding our use of cookies with PointRoll Ads.

**Information You Provide.** We may collect and store information that you voluntarily supply to us while on our Site, such as when you sign up for electronic newsletters or other email from PointRoll or when you use an app. This may include information that can be used to contact or identify you, such as your name, email address, or postal address. Some examples of this type of information include password information, user ID and location information (e.g., city and state and/or zip code). . If you do not consent to this collection of your Personal Information and its use as described in this policy, do not provide any Personal Information on this Site.

**Use of Information Collected on the Site.** PointRoll may use any information submitted on the Site or the Apps by a user for the purpose for which the information was submitted and for its other purposes, including to understand how users interact with the Site and the Apps, to contact the user for customer service purposes, to inform the user of important changes or additions to the Site or the services offered by the Site, and to send the user administrative notices and any other communications, including promotional messages, that PointRoll believes may be of interest to the user. We may use device and browser unique identifiers or IP addresses to identify the geographical location of the device or computer.

If you have subscribed to one or more of our email newsletters, you also may change your subscriber information, modify your subscriptions, and/or unsubscribe from these communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in the email you receive.

**Links to Other Sites.** The Site may include links to other websites. Those websites will have their own privacy policies that you may wish to review. PointRoll has no responsibility for these linked websites.

**Sharing and Disclosing Information.** PointRoll may share and disclose information that PointRoll collects to affiliates, service providers or Publishers for the purpose of providing services requested on the Site by a user, for purposes related to Site administration and other services, including sending promotional messages. PointRoll also may release information that PointRoll collects in order to comply with law, or to protect the rights, property or safety of advertisers, publishers, users, the public or PointRoll. Also, in the event that PointRoll sells some or all of its assets, reorganizes, is liquidated, is involved in a spin-off of ownership interest or is acquired by another company, information that PointRoll collects may be transferred in connection with that transaction.

**Access and Correction.  **PointRoll will provide the ability for user to have reasonable access and the ability to correct inaccurate Personal Information in response to inquiries directed to: Linda Carducci, lcarducc at tegna.com, Online Privacy Coordinator, PointRoll, c/o TEGNA Law Department, 7950 Jones Branch Drive, McLean, VA 22107

**Security.** The security of your information is very important to us. All information we gather on the Site is stored on secure servers and our internal systems. While we implement security measures to help safeguard your data,, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our servers or databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

**Children’s Privacy Statement.** PointRoll does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from a child under 13.

### 2\. ADVERTISING SERVED THROUGH POINTROLL AND POINTROLL AD DELIVERY OR MARKETING SERVICES OFF OF THIS SITE

**PointRoll makes digital advertising better — for the Advertiser and for the Viewer** **.** Our technology enables Advertisers and Publishers to better market to consumers with more relevant and engaging digital advertising so that consumers who view PointRoll Ads (“Viewers”) receive advertising that is of greater interest to them. The descriptions below explain our privacy practices with regard to advertising that PointRoll creates and delivers for our customers, and which appear on many different websites, applications and other digital platforms.

**Collection within PointRoll Ads.** PointRoll may collect and store Non-Personal Information that is generated automatically as a Viewer sees and interacts with PointRoll Ads. At the request of Advertisers or Publishers, PointRoll may also assist in the collection of Non-Personal Information of Viewers by third parties conducting research.

In certain cases, at the request of an Advertiser or Publisher, a PointRoll Ad may be designed to enable the collection of Personal Information from Viewers, such as a location (town of residence or zip code), gender, or email address, from within the PointRoll Ad. If you do not consent to collection of your PI, do not supply any Personal Information in a PointRoll Ad. Any Personal Information about a Viewer that is collected by a PointRoll Ad is provided to the Advertiser or Publisher or its authorized service provider and is not used by PointRoll for any other purpose. The Advertiser or Publisher’s collection and use of data, including the Personal Information of Viewers, is defined by the Advertiser or Publisher’s privacy policy. PointRoll does not control and is not responsible for Advertisers’ or Publishers’ privacy or information practices.

In some cases, a Viewer may choose to provide information about another person through a PointRoll Ad. For example, a PointRoll Ad may provide the functionality through which a Viewer may choose to provide a friend’s email address in order to forward a PointRoll Ad to a friend. As with any Personal Information that the Viewer supplies about him or herself, any Personal Information about another person that is collected by a PointRoll Ad is provided to the Advertiser or Publisher or its authorized service provider. The Advertiser or Publisher’s collection and use of the Personal Information of friends is defined by the Advertiser or Publisher’s privacy policy. PointRoll does not control and is not responsible for Advertisers’ or Publishers’ privacy or information practices.

In some cases, information that is voluntarily supplied by users within a PointRoll Ad in connection with certain third-party services is provided to the third party. The third party’s collection and use of the information of Viewers is defined by that third party’s privacy policy. PointRoll does not control and is not responsible for the third party’s privacy or information practices.

**Non-Personal Information Collected within PointRoll Ads and from Other Sources.** PointRoll may use Non-Personal Information of Viewers collected within PointRoll Ads to better target advertisements, improve the user experience, including to better direct PointRoll Ads to specific types of visitors, and/or to measure PointRoll Ad effectiveness.

**PointRoll Cookies.** PointRoll may collect Non-Personal Information of Viewers through a variety of technologies and practices including PointRoll’s or other third party’s browser cookies, web beacons or similar technologies. A cookie is a small file that can be automatically stored on a computer when the computer’s browser views an advertisements or a website. Similar to our practices on this Site, described above, PointRoll uses several different cookies within PointRoll Ads for a variety of purposes. We use our own cookies for purposes that include:

• measuring the effectiveness of PointRoll Ads, such as measurements relating to the impressions, reach, frequency, advertisement interactions, and conversions relating to the display of a PointRoll Ad);

• setting delivery specifications for PointRoll Ads; and

• analyzing our servers’ interactions with your browser.

For example, PointRoll may use cookies in connection with PointRoll Ads to collect Non-Personal Information, such as the approximate geographic location of the Viewer based on their IP address, the most recent Publisher websites that the Viewer’s browser has visited, or any PointRoll Ads that the Viewer has viewed or on which the Viewer has clicked. These data points are used alone or in combination to enable inferences about a Viewer (e.g., based on websites visited and ads clicked, a Viewer is likely to be a woman), their preferences (e.g., based on websites visited and ads clicked, a Viewer appears to like travel), or already expressed or implied interests in a product (e.g., to serve an ad based on a viewer’s previous interest in the advertiser’s website or ads, also known as “re-targeting so that we can better direct our advertising.

In using our cookies in connection with serving online advertisements, PointRoll may also use web beacons, consistent with industry practices, to measure the effectiveness of PointRoll Ads. PointRoll Ads may also use cookies to ensure the appropriate delivery of our Ads. For example, cookies control the order or sequencing we may present PointRoll Ads to allow PointRoll to show dynamic advertisements that evolve and change each time you see a PointRoll Ad from a particular advertiser.

PointRoll Ads are delivered via Privacy Preferences Projects (“P3P”)-compliant servers that communicate the details of PointRoll’s targeting advertising practices to P3P-enabled web browsers. Please note that we do not use “flash cookies” in connection with PointRoll Ads.

**Information from Third Parties.** In addition, PointRoll or the companies with which it does online business may use interest-based, retargeting and demographic data from third parties to help determine which PointRoll Ad is served to a particular Viewer. For example, geographic and purchase intent information passed from publishers via a cookie or other technologies to PointRoll may be used to deliver a geographically- or product-specific creative message to a consumer. For instance, a non-personally identifiable numeric code is shared via the data provider to the advertisement unit at run time via a cookie, which communicates a specific geographic area that is in turn read via the cookie by the PointRoll platform that will then select and serve the appropriate creative or message element associated with that geography.

**PointRoll Cookies Duration.** PointRoll currently sets cookies to be effective for no more than two years from the last interaction with a PointRoll domain or an Ad served by PointRoll, after which your browser should delete expired cookies. If you are concerned about historical cookies, we recommend that you clear your cookies using your web browser’s settings.

**Your Choices and Opting Out of Behavioral Advertising.** PointRoll respects consumer choices and preferences, and is committed to providing ways for Viewers to control their online experience. Please take a look at the below chart that explains the different categories of cookies used on our website and in PointRoll Ads and your choices regarding each.

**Purpose** | **Source** | **Where Used** | **Options**  
---|---|---|---  
Functionality | First party | PointRoll Site | These cookies facilitate the features available on our website. They enable you to use the site features as it was designed to be used. These cookies also allow us to remember choices you make and tailor the Site to provide enhanced features and content to you.As these cookies are required for the full functioning of this site, we do not provide select controls to disable them. You may, however, generally block them, along with all cookies, through browser settings, but note that Site functionality may be impaired.  
Performance | First party | PointRoll Site | These cookies are used to measure Site usage and evaluate Site performance.These cookies collect information about how people are using this Site, for example which pages are visited the most often, or how people are moving from one link to another and if they get error messages from certain pages. These cookies provide us with analytical information about how this Site is performing and how we can improve it. In some instances, these cookies tell us how we may tailor our advertising to make it more effective.You may generally block Performance cookies, along with all cookies, through browser settings.  
Third party | PointRoll Site  
Social Media | Third party | PointRoll Site PointRoll Ads | These cookies are used to enable you to interact with third-party social media sites.You may generally block Social Media cookies, along with all cookies, through browser settings, but note that Site or Ad functionality may be impaired.  
Advertising | First party | PointRoll Site PointRoll Ads | These cookies are used to deliver PointRoll Ads that may be more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see a particular advertisement, to sequence in what order you may see our advertisements, to present advertisements to those with an inferred interest in a product by visiting that company’s site, as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. These cookies contain information about PointRoll Ads you see and how you came to see them. They can remember that you have visited a website and this information may be shared with third parties, including Advertisers.You may opt-out or opt-in to the use of these cookies using the link provided below.  
Third party | PointRoll Ads  
  
A Viewer can Opt Out of receiving cookies that enable the Viewer’s browser to receive targeted PointRoll ads by clicking here or on the Opt-Out image below.

If a Viewer changes his or her mind after opting out (because he or she decides receiving tailored advertising is preferable to receiving generic ads), the Viewer can opt in by clicking the Opt-In link below.

opt-out opt-in

Note: This Opt-Out process provides a PointRoll opt-out cookie to the user’s browser. Therefore, if cookies are disabled, erased, or altered, or browser and/or machine software is changed, then the results of this opt-out process may be undone, and the Opt-Out will need to be performed again.

Alternatively, the Viewer’s web browser may allow a user to disable cookies. To disable cookies using Internet Explorer, select “Internet Options” under the Tools menu and click on “Privacy.” Select “High” or “Block All Cookies.” To disable cookies using Mozilla Firefox, select “Options” under the “Tools” menu. To check your cookie setting on Safari, select “Preferences” from the Safari menu, and then select either “Privacy” (versions 5.1 and later) or “Security” (versions 5.0.x and earlier). PointRoll does not use Flash Cookies but Adobe’s Flash Player Settings Manager allows you to customize the websites which you allow to use local storage (“Flash Cookies”). If a user chooses to disable cookies, a user may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the PointRoll Ads.

Depending on the Viewer’s individual browser settings, some anti-spyware software programs may erroneously flag PointRoll advertisements or cookies as computer threats. PointRoll does not knowingly distribute viruses or any computer code that monitors or causes changes to users’ computer system registries as part of its advertisements or cookies.

**Further Options for Obtaining Information About Your Choices and Opting Out of Behavioral Advertising.** PointRoll participates in industry self-regulatory groups and adheres to guidelines such as those of the [Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA)](http://www.aboutads.info/), a cooperative of companies committed to building responsible advertising policies across the Internet.

PointRoll is also a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and is in compliance with all NAI Principles. Users can obtain information about advertising service providers’ information collection practices, and opt out of such practices (and at the same time opt out of the collection practices of other, or all, NAI members) by following the opt out instructions at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.

Note, however, that certain opt-out functionality may require that third-party cookies be permitted. For example, the DAA cookie-blocking function cannot be utilized by a user with a Safari browser that is set to block third-party cookies (which is the default setting). However, the user may be able to change the settings temporarily to accept a DAA third-party cookie, and then restore the Safari default setting to block new third party cookies.

**Sharing and Disclosing Information.** PointRoll may share the information collected in a PointRoll Ad with the Advertiser. For example, if a user has opted in to receive email marketing from the Advertiser, PointRoll will share information collected in the Advertiser’s PointRoll Ad with that Advertiser. PointRoll may occasionally release information that PointRoll collects from PointRoll Ads in order to comply with law, or to protect the rights, property or safety of advertisers, publishers, users, the public or PointRoll. Also, in the event that PointRoll sells some or all of its assets, or PointRoll is acquired by another company, information that PointRoll collects may be among the transferred assets.

**Questions/Concerns:**

If you have any questions regarding PointRoll’s privacy policy, data security practices, information collection or uses, or have any concerns or disputes regarding your information, please contact:  
Linda Carducci, lcarducc at tegna.com

Online Privacy Coordinator, PointRoll  
c/o TEGNA Law Department  
7950 Jones Branch Drive  
McLean, VA 22107.
